A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, United States International Affairs Program (USIAP), Education and Culture, Office Files of Peter W. Stanley FA603
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Meeting and trip files, 1980-1991; 3; 2.57 Cubic Feet About 6.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  - Hispanic Task Force meeting, 1983-1985 (Box 23, Folder 204)
  - Conference - Alison Bernstein, undated (Box 23, Folder 205)
  - Trustees Meeting, 1981-1985 (Box 23, Folder 206)
  - Trustees Meeting, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - Trustees Remarks, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Trustees Meeting, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - A. Bartlett Giamatti - Trustees Meeting notes, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 210)
  - Trustees reports, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - David Laird, Jr., 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Education and Culture Planning Meetings 1,2, and 3, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 213-214)
  - Education and Culture Planning Meeting 4 - Desegregation Support, 1980-1983 (Box 24, Folder 215-217)
    First and second mailing
    Post-Meeting comments
    Invitees
    Miscellaneous information: Hotel, etc.
    Papers for meeting
  - Desegregation Support meeting follow-up, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Adams Desegregation Activity meeting - Southern Education Foundation (SEF), 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Meetings (individuals, foundations, universities), 1988-1990 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - Meetings - Program development discussions (individuals, foundations, universities), 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 221-223)
    James D. Koerner – Sloan Foundation – 10/84
    10/22/84 – Harvard University/Fletcher School
    10/25-26/84 – Smithsonian Institution/American Council on Education (ACE)/Association of American Universities (AAU)/National Association of College University Attorneys (NACUA)
    Harvard University Divinity School – 9/27/84 – George Rupp/Constance Buchanan
    C. Dwight Lahr/Jerry Nunnally – Dartmouth College – 10/10/84
    Cornelius Pings – 10/10/84 – University of Southern California
    Institute of International Education (IIE) – Eleanor Barber – 11/14/84
    Lincoln Center Theater meeting at Ford Foundation - 7/22/85
  - Meetings (individuals, foundations, universities), 1985-1987 (Box 25, Folder 224-225)
  - Education and Culture meetings (with outside personnel regarding funding requests), 1983-1984 (Box 25, Folder 226)
  - Meetings (individuals, foundations, universities), 1987-1989 (Box 26, Folder 227-229)
  - Jose Abueva, University of the Philippines, visit, 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 230)
  - Work file - National Council on Foreign Languages and International Studies (NCFLIS)/Smithsonian Institution, 1984-1986 (Box 26, Folder 231)
  - Work file - University of Michigan (John H. D'Arms), 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 232)
  - Cornell University, 1984-1985 (Box 26, Folder 233)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education (COFHE), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 234)
  - Swarthmore College Conference on the Recruitment and Retention of Minority Students, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 235)
  - The College Board meeting, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 236)
  - New York University meeting, 1983-1984 (Box 26, Folder 237)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) meeting, 1980-1984 (Box 27, Folder 238)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) Annual Meeting, San Diego, California, 1988-1989 (Box 27, Folder 239)
  - Work file - American Association of Universities (AAU) Graduate Research Center (Bob Rosenzweig), 1985 (Box 27, Folder 240)
  - Work file - University of Arizona (Peter W. Culicover), 1985 (Box 27, Folder 241)
  - Work file - Association of American Colleges (AAC) (Irving J. Spitzberg), 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 242)
  - Work file - Atwell, Robert, American Council on Education (ACE) (regarding international endowment task force), 1985 (Box 27, Folder 243)
  - Work file - Daedalus (Stephen Graubard), 1985 (Box 27, Folder 244)
  - Work file - Richard Larson (writing programs), 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 245)
  - Work file - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Dean Ann F. Friedlaender), 1985 (Box 27, Folder 246)
  - Work file - Stanford University School of Education (Myron Atkin and Ingram Olkin), 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 247)
  - Work file - The College Board (Donald Stewart), 1988-1990 (Box 27, Folder 248)
  - Work file - Great Lakes colleges Association (GLCA) (Jon Fuller/John Eadie), 1988 (Box 27, Folder 249)
  - Work file - San Antonio, Texas project (Susan Berresford/Gordon Berlin), 1987 June 11 (Box 27, Folder 250)
  - Work file - Urban School Dropout Prevention Collaboratives (Edward Meade, Jr.), 1988-1989 (Box 27, Folder 251)
  - Work file - Wayne State University (Bob Berg), 1988 January 19 (Box 27, Folder 252)
  - The Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Tufts University - Seminar on Philanthropy and Foreign Relations, 1984-1988 (Box 27, Folder 253)
  - Desk file - Frank Heny, consultant, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 254)
  - Research Libraries Group, Inc. (RLG), 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 255)
  - Desk file - Cornell University (David McCann, Barry Adams), 1985 (Box 28, Folder 256)
  - Work file - Boston Plan for Excellence in the Public Schools, Boston Compact (Kenneth Rossano), 1985-1988 (Box 28, Folder 257)
  - Desk file - Harvard University (David Riesman), 1984-1987 (Box 28, Folder 258)
  - Desk file - Bennett M. Berger University of California San Diego, 1984-1987 (Box 28, Folder 259)
- General files, 1986-1992; 4; .57 Cubic Feet About 1.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  Series consists of the files in Peter W. Stanley's records that were marked as general. Their content and structure are similar to that of the Chronological correspondence files in Series 1. They contain correspondence, alphabetically arranged by the name of the correspondent. Most of the correspondents found within the general files are institutions and organizations that discussed Ford Foundation grant support with Stanley.
  - 1991 General file, 1986-1992 (Box 28, Folder 260-263)
  - 1989-1990 General file, 1988-1990 (Box 29, Folder 264-268)